Go, Eren!
In the year 850,
humanity successfully took back land
from the Titans for the very first time.
At great cost.
All of you here are hereby accepted
as new members
of the Scout Regiment!
This is a genuine salute!
Give your hearts!
Yes, Sir!
You've done well to endure your fear.
You're all brave soldiers.
I respect you from the bottom of my heart.
One month later,
the Scout Regiment, led by Erwin Smith,
left Calaneth District to
establish a route to Shiganshina,
which is believed to
house a secret of the Titans.
Now commencing the
57th Exterior Scouting Mission!
Move out!
I won't let your deaths be meaningless
even if I'm the last one standing
In both hands, Gloria
What sings is Sieg
On my back, Flügel der Freiheit
Clenched determination to my left chest
What slashes across is Linie der Torheit
Soaring across the azure skies
Flügel der Freiheit
"Female Titan"
"The 57th Exterior Scouting Mission, Part 1"
10-meter Titan ahead,
approaching from the left!
I'm extremely curious to
know what's inside its stomach!
But I'll let the support squad handle it!
Damn! Not deep enough!
Defend the ranks!
Don't falter!
Leave it to the support squad!
Keep moving!
Forward!
The support squad will only
cover us until we're through the old city.
Everything beyond
that is wholly Titan territory.
From then on,
we'll have to rely on Commander
Erwin's long-range scouting formation.
Our special operations
squad will be positioned here.
Mr. Oruo!
Do you think they--my classmates--
can beat the Titans in a fight?
Huh? What the hell did you just
spend this last month doing?!
Listen, kid!
Outside scouting missions
are about fighting Titans
as little as possi--
Assume long-range scouting formation!
See you later, Armin.
Don't wet your pants
if you run into a Titan!
Right! Likewise to you!
"Row 3-3: Signaling"
This formation is a forward-facing semicircle,
with soldiers positioned
"Row 5, Center: Standby"
far from each other at equal intervals
"Row 2-5: Signaling"
yet still within clear sight on all sides.
Extend the spotting
"Row 3-4: Signaling"
and signaling range as far as possible!
"Row 2-4: Signaling"
It's okay. Stay calm.
The soldiers in the front-row spotting
squads will encounter most of the Titans.
"Row 1-8: Spotting"
As soon as they spot a Titan
they'll fire a red smoke signal.
Soldiers who see this signal
will then signal others similarly.
"Row 2, Center: Command"
Once the commander has
learned of the Titan's position,
he'll fire a green signal
and reroute the
entire platoon around it.
This will allow the platoon
to proceed toward its destination
while avoiding the Titans entirely.
"Row 2-3: Signaling"
However, as the terrain and other
obstacles could delay their detection,
we may encounter
Titans inside the formation.
R-Red... Red signal...!
Braus! Over here!
Damn! The spotters missed one!
Let's lure it this way!
Braus! Run toward us!
Break away! I'll handle this!
Yes, Sir!
Sir!
It's conked out!
Return to your position!
Something's not right...
It's been a while since the last red signal,
yet the formation's in disarray.
Could it be...?
Keep in mind, this strategy
will only work with "Normals,"
Titans with predictable behavior.
A black smoke signal?!
It's ignoring everyone nearby
and heading straight for
the center of the formation?!
No doubt about it! It's...
...an Abnormal!
Only when dealing with unpredictable
Abnormals is combat necessary!
Damn! No choice but to fight!
Cis! You go for its nape!
I'll stop it in its tracks!
Understood!
An ODM battle on level ground
puts us at a clear disadvantage.
Our chances of success are incredibly low,
but we can't afford to
let it wreck our formation!
Arlelt's that way, as I recall.
I can't let a rookie face this thing!
I'm taking it out here!
Now, Cis!
Way to go, Section Commander Ness!
Got it!
You came! You're my horse, all right!
I love ya, Charrette!
Another one?! What are
the right wing spotters doing?!
It must be an Abnormal too.
It's ignoring everyone on its way here.
Ugh, all right...
Let's do it again, Cis!
Yes, Sir!
Man, two in a row...
Talk about unlucky.
Plus, this one looks
to be 14-meters high.
This is gonna be tough.
What the...! It's way too fast!
Don't let it go for Arlelt!
Cis!
Yes, Sir!
No! This one's different!
This isn't an Abnormal...
It has intelligence!
It's just like the Armored Titan,
the Colossal Titan, and Eren!
It's a human clad in a Titan body!
B-But who?! Why?!
This is bad! What do I do?!
It's going to kill me too!
Go! Run for it!
What is its--
No, what is their...
...goal?!
S-Someone, let the others know...
The right wing spotting squads...
are almost entirely wiped out...
A female-looking Titan...
brought a horde of Titans with her...
Is... anyone left...?
It... didn't kill me?
What just happened?
It pinched my hood and...
My face?
It checked my face?
Armin!
Reiner!
Hey, can you stand?!
There's no surviving outside
the wall without a horse, you know!
Hurry!
Mm!
I saw the Abnormal smoke signal.
Is it that one with the nice butt?
It's not an Abnormal!
It's a person clad in a Titan body!
What?!
Hold on! We need to
fire a smoke signal first!
H-Hurry. We have to let them know...
...there's an emergency--
Wait.
It looks like Jean fired for us.
From the right wing?!
They've suffered too severe of
an attack to continue the operation?!
Apparently part of the
right wing's been wiped out!
A whole horde of Titans showed up!
I dunno how it happened, though!
A bunch of 'em are fast, too!
We're holding them off for now,
but no one's on spotting duty now!
This is a serious setback; if we're
not careful we could all get wiped out!
That's the direction she came from...
Could it be?
Did she lead the Titans here?!
She?
What's a Titan doing there?!
Is it an Abnormal?!
No, it's a human clad in a Titan body.
A human who can
do the same thing as Eren.
What?!
What makes you think that, Armin?
"Eating" is all that Titans do.
This results in death of course,
but "killing" isn't their actual goal.
But as soon as more experienced
soldiers went for her vital spot,
she crushed and swatted them down.
And she didn't do it to eat them...
she did it to kill them.
She's unlike any other Titan in that regard.
She must've been the one
who brought the hordes of Titans
when the Colossal and Armored
Titans destroyed the walls.
Meaning she's had the consistent
goal of attacking humankind.
Or, actually...
I think she might be searching for someone.
If so, who?
Could it be Eren?!
Eren?
Eren's with the Levi Squad.
They're in charge of the right wing.
Right wing?
My copy of the plan had
them in the rear of the left wing.
My copy placed them
at the front of the right wing...
Wait, there's no way they'd
be put on the front lines like that.
Then where are they?
The safest place in
this formation, I'd assume.
Which would be...
...the rear of the center rank.
Armin!
This is no time to get lost in thought!
Smoke signals aren't enough to
explain how much of a threat she poses!
At this rate, she'll take
out the command squad too.
And if that happens, the formation
falls apart and we all die!
What are you suggesting?
I'm suggesting that from this distance
we might still be able to distract her.
We can buy some time
for everyone to retreat.
Maybe, anyway...
She really does have intelligence.
From her point of view,
we're literally just like insects.
All it takes is one swipe to kill us.
You don't say...
That's some scary stuff.
Are you really Jean?
The Jean I know only
ever cares about himself.
That's rude.
I just don't want to
meet a disappointing end
as a bunch of burnt bones
that you can't even tell are mine.
I... I know what needs to be done now!
Plus, we chose to take this job!
Help me!
Put your hoods on! All the way,
so she can't see your face!
Because she can't risk killing
us if she can't tell who we are!
I get it.
She can't risk killing
anyone who might be Eren.
Now that's a relief to know.
Here's hoping she's
got bad eyesight too!
Armin...
The way you always clung so
close to Eren used to creep me out,
but I always knew I could count on you.
Huh? Oh, thanks.
But that's mean, thinking I'm creepy...
She's a lot slower than
when she came from that way.
Is she tired?
If she takes off at that
speed again we'll be too late!
We have to do it now!
We have to act now, or else...!
All right, guys.
Do it like we just discussed.
Distract her for as long as possible
so the platoon can retreat!
We hafta keep her here as long as we can!
Cutting her heel tendons
should be more than enough.
But don't do anything crazy.
We don't need to kill her!
She's aware of the
vital spot on her nape.
She's completely different
from the other Titans.
Killing her is probably out of the question.
At least for ordinary people, anyway.
But maybe those two could...!
Armin!
This one's way more athletic
than the other ones!
Damn! We were...
We were too naïve!
She's protecting her nape?!
Jean!
Damn! There's no escape now!
I'm dead! She's gonna
grab my wire and finish me!
Jean! Avenge that suicidal maniac!
Armin?
She stopped?
It was her! She killed him!
That maniac finally got himself killed,
as part of the right wing!
She killed him!
What's going on?!
Did he hit his head and get confused?!
This is the worst possible time...!
Reiner...
She crushed my friend!
I saw him stuck to the bottom of her foot!
He's going straight for the nape?!
No, he can do it! Now's his chance,
while she's focused on Armin!
H-Hey...
H-Hey!
Reiner... You...
Ol' Reiner actually did it...!
Mikasa stole so much
of the spotlight that I forgot
that he's extremely skilled
and dependable too!
I'd say we bought enough time!
Now let's get away from her, quick!
She doesn't eat people!
I don't think she'll follow us!
Look! The giant wench is running
home with her tail between her legs!
Huh? Oh no...
Why?
The rear of the center rank is that way...
Is she heading for Eren?!
If, by chance, I'm not me
then who's to say that you're you?
Can you pick up the pieces of your heart
that fell apart like a broken sand castle?
The voice of someone calling out
changed into ringing in my ears
It's as if time has stopped
Now wake up
I made my way out of the deep darkness
I fled like a swift wind
We used to be like living corpses,
but now we head beyond the walls
Let's meet again
in a place not on any map
"You monster!"
Not even the highly trained Scout
Regiment can stop the Female Titan.
Eventually, inside a forest of giant trees,
the monster finally catches sight of Eren.
"Forest of Giant Trees"
"The 57th Exterior Scouting Mission, Part 2"